Space debris, loose material generated
as a result of space development,
（ナレーション）宇宙開発の
結果として出た廃棄物―
スペースデブリは
実は とても危険な存在です
...is a very serious threat.
This is a story of 2075, a time in which
this space garbage has become a problem.
これは 2075年―
宇宙のゴミが
問題になった時代の物語
Our recurring profits are maintaining
a steady growth of 15%.
（クレア）経常利益は
15パーセント成長を維持しています
Second Department is at
the top again this quarter.
今期も 第２事業部がトップですね
Yes, but Second Department also has
a section that's running in the red.
（ドルフ）我が第２事業部にも
赤字の部署はある
Half Section, sir?
（クレア）半課ですか？
（ドルフ）うーん…
（クレア）あっ…
My apologies, sir.
Debris Section.
失礼しました デブリ課です
As you know, debris collection
expenses are paid according to environmental
points set by INTO.
（ドルフ）知ってのとおり
デブリ回収の費用は―
連合の定める
環境点数に応じて支払われる
But they're just
bureaucratic figures.
だが 所詮は官僚の数字
They don't necessarily provide enough
points to cover our expenses.
必ずしも
費用に見合う点数はついていない
In other words, to bring them into
the black, we need to get INTO...
（クレア）つまり 黒字にするには
連合から点数の高いデブリを―
...to assign us debris
that has a high point value.
割り当ててもらう
必要があるということですね
Nevertheless...
しかし…
（ドルフ）だからだ
Which brings me to my point.
あっ…
Claire-kun, could I ask you
to do something for me?
クレア君
１つ 頼まれてくれないか？
What would that be, sir?
何でしょうか？
♪～
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪幾千の朝に
♪光が向かう場所へ
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
Target acquisition.
You copy?
（ハチマキ）
対象物合わせ ユー コピー？
I copy.
（タナベ）アイ コピー
（ハチマキ）ズーム
Zoom in.
I copy.
（タナベ）アイ コピー
ヒット確認
Hit confirmed.
Target change.
Yaw right.
（ハチマキ）
ターゲットチェンジ 要ライト
I copy.
（タナベ）アイ コピー
Huh? What the...?
あっ… あら… あら
Like I keep telling you, you always
open up too many windows!
（ハチマキ）だからさあ
お前は何でも出し過ぎなんだよ
I told you to keep it simple, didn't I?
もっとシンプルに
しとけって言ったろ
Phase 4
Part of the Job
You got that, rookie?!
分かったか？ 新入り
（タナベ）
その新入りっての―
Could you please stop with
that "rookie" stuff?
いいかげん
やめてください
It's been a whole month
since I started here.
（タナベ）ここに来てから
もう１か月たつんですよ
Only a month,
you mean.
（ハチマキ）まだ １か月だ
So how many months will it be
before you call me by my name?
（タナベ）
じゃあ 何か月 たったら―
ちゃんと名前で
呼んでくれるんですか？
Say, is this hairspray?
（コリン）
ねえ これ ヘアスプレーだよね？
（ハチマキ）あ？
（コリン）忘れちゃってさ
I forgot to bring any. My hair
is a mess because of this zero-G.
無重力のせいで グチャグチャ
誰だ？ てめえ
Who the hell are you?
Wow, what cheap stuff!
（コリン）うっわ 安物
Hey! I'm asking you
a question, buddy!
（ハチマキ）
おい 誰だっつってんだよ！
Didn't anyone tell you to give your own name
before asking someone else's?
（コリン）人に名前を尋ねるときは
まず自分からって習わなかった？
- Moron!
Oh, well.
まあ いいや
僕 コリン･クリフォード
知ってるかな？
I'm Colin Clifford.
Maybe you've heard of me?
Clifford...
（ラビィ）クリフォード…
Clifford?!
クリフォード！？
I'm sure I know
that name!
その お名前は 確か！
何ですか？ これ
What's this book?
A file of key people that you need
to know to survive here at Technora!
（ラビィ）テクノーラ社で
生きていく上で―
重要な人々のファイルだ！
（コリン）フッ…
What do you mean
by key people?
重要な人々って…
上司とクライアント
Bosses and clients. In a company,
you'll be just fine if you know who's who.
会社ってのは
そこを抑えておけば まず大丈夫
これ 覚えておいたほうがいいから
You'd do well
to remember that.
Found it!
あったー！
Jentro Clifford.
Chairman of... INTO?!
“ジェントロ･クリフォード
連合の… 議長”！？
その下
Under that!
Eldest son, William.
Second son...
“長男 ウィリアム 次男…”
コリン･クリフォード
Colin Clifford.
（ハチマキ）何？
What?
（課長）ん…
（フィー）ふーん
（コリン）
分かっていただけました？
So, are we all
clear on that now?
Yeah, so what?
（ハチマキ）だから何だってんだ？
Non-personnel aren't
allowed into this office, so...
俺たちの仕事場は
部外者 立ち入り禁止なんだが… と
It doesn't look much like
an office to me...
仕事場には見えないけどね
あ？
（猫の鳴き声）
（課長）んぐ…
し… 素人が
何 偉そうなこと言ってんだ
W-Who do you think you are,
you amateur?
Anyway, unauthorized personnel keep us
from doing our work, so get out!
それより 部外者は
邪魔なんだから出てけよ！
あっ…
あっ 管制課の…
That's that lady
from Control...
You're just in time, Claire-san.
（コリン）
助かりましたよ クレアさん
These people don't seem to be interested
in hearing what I have to say.
僕の話 聞く気がないみたいで
I'm terribly sorry.
申し訳ありません
本日のデブリ回収には―
He and I will be accompanying
you on today's debris retrieval.
私と彼が同行します
よろしいですね？
That's all right, I assume?
勝手に決めんなよ
Don't assume anything! Why should we let
Control Section foist off this daddy's boy...
管制課のわがままで ボンボン…
Of course it's okay!
もう よろしいったら
ありゃしないですよ
Okay like the O.K. Corral!
We're with you 120%!
ＯＫ牧場
120パーセントでございます
Good to have you
on board.
よろしく
（鳴き声）
（課長）
おお！ 法学部にご在籍ですか
Oh, so you're in law school,
are you?
You're planning on becoming
a lawyer, then?
（ラビィ）
では 将来は弁護士の先生に？
It doesn't matter
what kind of degree I get.
（コリン）
学部なんて どこでも一緒
My father will get me into any job I want, so all
I really need is the title of college graduate.
どうせ
就職は親父(おやじ)が世話するんだから
要は大卒って
肩書があればいいんですよ
あの 私の…
Um, those are my...
That's the way the world works,
isn't it?
世の中って
そういうもんですよね？
Yes, it certainly is...
いえ 全くです
How wise of you
to notice!
さすが よくご存じで
ほら タナベ君
コーヒー お出しして
Psst, Tanabe-kun!
Get the man some coffee.
ああ 要らないい
（ラビィ）はっ？
That's all right.
（コリン）安いでしょ？ ここの
You only have cheap
stuff here, right?
Oops, you certainly
have us there!
いやあ
これは 一本取られましたなあ
Do you have any cola?
Something that isn't light or diet.
コーラある？ ライトとか
ダイエットじゃないやつ
タナベ君 コーラ
（タナベ）ありませんよ そんなの
Tanabe-kun, get him a cola!
We don't have any cola.
買ってきて！
Then go buy some!
Oh, let the girl stay here.
ああ 女の子は置いといてよ
It's no fun talking to old guys, you know?
おじさんとしゃべってても
楽しくないでしょ？
Yessir! I'll go buy some
right away!
はっ では
私が買いに行かせていただきます
Fine, be quick
about it.
（コリン）うん 早くね
（ラビィ）はっ
Yes, sir!
ウーン 変身！
Transform into Ultra Lavie!
It's me... Right...
ああ 私です
（ラビィ）
レーザービーム！
ええ DS-12を
ＶＩＰゲートに移してください
Please move the DS-12
to the VIP gate.
ええ DS-12を
ＶＩＰゲートに移してください
Hey, don't plan things out on your own.
（ハチマキ）
おい 勝手に段取るなよ
I haven't okayed anything.
俺は許可してないぞ
He's only here to observe debris collection.
We won't interfere with your work.
（クレア）
デブリ回収を見学するだけです
業務に支障はないはずですが？
（ハチマキ）断る
No way.
This is an order from the Departmental Director.
事業部長命令です
（ハチマキ）あっ…
Why does it have to be us?
Go make the PR Section do it!
なんで俺たちなんだよ
そういうのは
広報課にでも言えよな
We're doing this to help you.
あなたたちのために やってるのよ
ああ？
（フィー）つまり―
In other words, you're doing INTO a favor to get
them to assign us some good debris. Right?
連合に恩を売って―
おいしいデブリを
回してもらおうってこと
（フィー）でしょ？
You'll never turn a profit if you collect nothing
but debris with low environmental points.
環境点数の低いデブリばかりでは
黒字は望めませんから
Hey... If we turn a profit, will you
build us a smoking room?
ねえ 黒字になったら
喫煙室 作ってくれる？
That thing is a little cramped.
あれ 窮屈なんだよね
検討しましょ
We'll consider it.
（フィー）よっしゃあ！ 商談成立
Sweet! We have a deal!
Hachi! You're a grown man,
so get over it!
ハチ あんたも大人なら
割り切りな！
If that's settled, then...
では そういうことで
Aw, come on...
おいおい
（クレア）コリンさん
Colin-san?
Oh, we're going already?
（コリン）ああ もう行くの？
じゃあ 続きは船の中で
（課長）ああ…
Let's pick up where we left off
aboard the ship, shall we?
（ラビィ）お坊ちゃま
このアルヴィンド･ラビィが―
Young master! I, Arvind Lavie, have taken
the liberty of providing you with a cola!
コーラをば
ご用意させていただきました
Hm? I don't
need it anymore.
（コリン）あ？ もう 要らない
（ラビィ）あへえ
（課長）
それでは お気をつけて
Take care, then!
I hope you make
some fond memories!
（ラビィ）
よい思い出を お作りください
See you!
（コリン）じゃあね
Hey, Hachimaki,
I thought you had five people on board.
（キース）おい ハチマキ
乗員は５人じゃなかったのか？
It's six. Somebody from Control, and a social
studies student who's here to observe.
（ハチマキ）６人だよ
管制課のやつと 社会見学の学生
勝手に増やすなよ
Don't add people
without telling us!
Besides, you've gotta get authorization
to carry non-personnel passengers!
それに 社外の人なら
ちゃんと許可 取れって
If they don't have permission,
they can't go?
（ハチマキ）
許可 取らないと駄目？
Of course not!
（キース）当たり前だ
You heard the man!
Gee, that's too bad.
だってさ 残念だったな
I guess your field trip
will have to wait.
見学は また今度ってことで
（ヘリック）
ああ いいんだ いいんだ
Hey, it's okay, it's okay.
He's cleared.
この方はいいんだ
ああ？
I heard about it
from the bosses.
お話は 上司から聞いております
He's you-know-who's son.
例の息子
あっ 失礼しました
Sorry about that, sir!
Five passengers confirmed.
Please go right ahead, sir.
乗員５名で確認
どうぞ お通りください
Huh? Five people?
Me, Senpai, Fee-san, Yuri-san, the Control lady...
えっ ５人って―
私と 先輩と
フィーさんと ユーリさんと―
管制課の人と…
コリンさんは？
What about you, Colin-san?
（コリン）まっ
これが世の中ってもんですよね
This is how the
world works.
The way the world works,
my ass...
（ハチマキ）何が世の中だよ
（ラビィ）タナベ君
（課長）愛(あい)ちゃん
Tanabe-kun!
Ai-chan!
はい
（課長）頼んだよ 愛ちゃん
Sir?
We're counting on you, Ai-chan!
（ラビィ）ハチのやつが
無礼を働かないよう―
We need you to smooth things over
to make sure Hachi doesn't insult him!
フォロー よろしく
（タナベ）ええっ 私が？
Huh? Why me?
The Chairman of INTO
could have an employee of a civilian corporation fired
so fast his head would spin!
（課長）
連合の議長にとっちゃ―
一民間企業の社員を
クビにするなんて―
わけないんだよ！
（ラビィ）
君はコリンさんと年も近いしさ
Plus, you're about the
same age as Colin.
Tanabe-san!
（ユーリ）タナベさーん
Stop fooling around,
rookie!
（ハチマキ）何 遊んでんだ 新入り
（タナベ）は… はい 今すぐ
C-Coming!
I'll be right there!
頼むよ 愛ちゃん
I'm counting on you, Ai-chan!
I couldn't possibly start a new career at my age!
この年で
今更 再就職なんてできないよ
And I have seven hungry children
to feed back on Earth!
私も 地球には
おなかをすかせた７人の子供が
I understand, I'll try to rein in Senpai.
Somehow...
分かりましたよ
先輩を抑えてみます なんとか
Make sure!
絶対？
（ラビィ）ユー コピー？
You copy?!
アイ コピーです！
Yes sir, I copy!
Yes, sir.
（ドルフ）はい はい
いえ とんでもありません
Yes, sir...
It's no trouble at all, sir.
We'll deal with the matter secretly, of course.
もちろん 秘密裏に
処理させていただきます
Just leave everything to us, Chairman Clifford.
お任せください
クリフォード議長
その代わり
デブリの割り当ての件は…
And in return, about those
debris assignments...
はい よろしく お願いします
Yes, sir. I look forward
to future dealings with you.
Okay, then...!
よーし
Next up
is a salute pose!
次は 敬礼のポーズ
ハハッ こりゃ 面白いや
This is fun!
Oops, that was close!
おっと 危ない
T-Try to be careful, okay?
（タナベ）
き… 気をつけてくださいね
So, will you let me do any
debris collecting later?
ねえ ついでに デブリ回収
僕にやらせてくれない？
（ハチマキ）
おい 遊びじゃねえんだぞ
Hey, this isn't
a game.
If I hear some student like you talking big,
you're going right out the airlock.
学生ごときが
偉そうに ほざくんなら―
放り出すからな
（タナベ）ちょっと 先輩
Senpai, can we talk?
What?
（ハチマキ）何だよ
He's the son of the
INTO Chairman...!
連合議長の息子さんなんですよ
議長なんて偉すぎて
俺たちデブリ屋には関係ねえよ
The Chairman's such a bigshot that he'd never
deign to touch us lowly debris collectors.
Yes, he does!
What if we get downsized?!
ありますよ
リストラされたらどうすんですか？
What about finding a new job?
Or our kids?
再就職とか 子供とか
What, you've got kids?
お前 子供いるのか？
ともかく ソフトに ね？ ね？
Anyway, let's
tread softly, okay?
Are you done with
your chat?
（コリン）話 まとまった？
ちゃんと お礼はするんだからさ
You'll be rewarded,
so you do your part...
そっちも それなりの… あ？
Hey! Don't bust
other people's ships!
てめえ 人様の船
壊してんじゃねえよ！
But doesn't that happen
all the time?
（タナベ）
いつものことじゃないですか
Oh, so you're on this guy's side,
huh, rookie?
（ハチマキ）ほう
新入りは こいつの味方なんだな
味方って…
On his side?
（コリン）んとに ボロい船だなあ
Wow, this ship is such a heap...
It doesn't hold a candle to the one my father owns.
親父が持ってるのとは ダンチだよ
えっ？
There really are some, Senpai!
Some people really do own their own ship!
いるんですね 先輩
個人で宇宙 船持ってる人って
Hear that? Individuals can
buy one of their own.
（ハチマキ）
ほら見ろ 個人でも買えるんだ
You still have
that notebook?
まだ持ってるの？ あのノート
悪いかよ
What's wrong
with that?
Nothing, really.
別に
I was just thinking
that you never change.
ただ 変わらないなあって
Hey, does this ship
have weapons?
（コリン）
ねえ この船 武器ってないの？
Like anti-debris missiles or
pulverization drills or something?
対デブリミサイルとか
粉砕用のドリルとか
（ハチマキ）ドリルなんて
あるわけねえだろうが！
Of course it doesn't
have a drill!
I wonder if Ha-chan is getting
along with Colin-san...
（課長）ハッちゃん コリンさんと
うまくやってるかなあ
Say...
ねえ ラビィちゃん
さっきから何してるの？
Lavie-chan, what's that that you've
been working on over there?
調べものです ハチマキが―
I'm doing research!
I thought maybe we could get a gift box of sweets
just in case Hachimaki does something rude...
失礼を働いたときに備えて
菓子折りでも…
Make it something soft, then!
The Chairman is getting on in years, remember?
だったら 軟らかい物がいいよ
議長さんって
結構 お年なんでしょ？
あっ さすがは課長
じゃあ セブン名物の―
That's our Chief!
How about Seven's local speciality,
"Cosmic Cream Puffs," then?
宇宙シュークリームなんて
どうでしょう
I hear they're really popular.
They supposedly sell out by noon.
人気あるんだってね
お昼すぎには売り切れるって
おっ… あっ 大変だ！
Oh, no!
Let's get going!
（ラビィ）早く行きましょう
Wait! My wallet!
（課長）待って お財布
（ラビィ）私が持ってます
I have mine!
（課長）
ラビィちゃん ちょっと待ってよ
Lavie-chan, wait for me!
Darn it, wait, I said!
待ってったら ほら
Don't dawdle!
It's time for our noon break,
so I'm going out to lunch.
（エーデル）
昼休みの時間ですので―
食事に行かせていただきます
Senpai...
（タナベ）先輩
（ハチマキ）何だ？
What?
（タナベ）管制課のクレアって人
お知り合いなんですか？
That Claire lady from Control...
Is she an acquaintance of yours?
あのノートのことも知ってたし
She knew about
your notebook, so...
Don't stop working,
rookie.
（ハチマキ）手を止めるな 新入り
It's Tanabe.
（タナベ）タナベです
We joined the company
at the same time.
（ハチマキ）同期入社だからな
Of course, we only talked to each other
for the first year or so.
もっとも
話したのは最初の１年ぐらいだ
向こうは管制課のエリート
こっちは半課でデブリ拾いだし
She's a Control Section elite, and I'm
a lowly Half Section debris hauler.
（タナベ）ふーん
This is a professional ship, but it's
nothing to write home about, is it?
プロ用って言っても
大したことないね
そうですか
You think so?
That's because we've got no budget.
（フィー）予算ないからさ
まっ どこも似たようなもんだって
Heck, it's the same story everywhere.
Really? That's so depressing...
へえ しょぼい話
We're back!
（タナベ）ただいま 帰りました
（フィー）ああ お疲れさん
Good work.
I was watching! You looked
pretty cool out there!
見てたよ カッコいいじゃない
あ… ありがとうございます
Thank you.
Hey, would you like to work part time
as my instructor later?
（コリン）ねえ 今度バイトで
インストラクターやらない？
は？
こないだ
仲間と宇宙遊泳したんだけど―
Some friends and I went spacewalking a
while ago, but we wound up all over the place.
ボロボロでさあ
えっ 素人だけでですか？
Huh? You weren't supervised
by a professional?!
We had a pro with us, but he was an old man
who did nothing but rag on us.
一応 プロはつけたよ
でも むさくて
うるさいおやじでね
A girl would be better,
don't you think?
やっぱり
女の子のほうがいいじゃない？
（ユーリ）フィーさん
Fee-san?
（フィー）終わった？ ユーリ
You finished, Yuri?
Yes. I put everything in the container,
Fishbone and all.
（ユーリ）
はい フィッシュボーンごと―
コンテナに入れてあります
I was planning on turning the whole thing
over to Materials Section back at Seven.
セブンで資材課に回すつもりですが
Sure, that's fine.
（フィー）ああ それでいいよ
Okay, all that's left now is to return to Seven,
so I'm adjusting our course to 24 degrees.
（フィー）じゃ
あとはセブンに帰るだけだから―
進路 24度に変更っと
（クレア）35度です
35 degrees.
（フィー）ん？
（タナベ）え？
（ハチマキ）あ？
Please make our heading 35 degrees.
（クレア）
進路は 35度でお願いします
おいおい 何言ってんだよ
Hey, now, what the hell
are you saying?
I want to show him the Yuukawa
communications satellite.
彼に 通信衛星ユウカを
見せてあげたいのですが
Gosh, I sure would love
to see the Yuukawa...
（コリン）見たいなあ ユウカは
We're supposed to make a little side-trip
on the way home from work?
（ハチマキ）
仕事帰りに 寄り道しろってのかよ
It's only a little way out of your orbit.
Fuel and air supplies shouldn't be a problem.
ほんの少し 軌道をずらすだけ
燃料も空気も 問題ないはずですが
That's not the point!
そういう問題じゃねえ
Departmental Director's orders.
事業部長の指示です
（ハチマキ）また それか！
That again?!
（フィー）進路35度に変更
Changing heading
to 35 degrees...
Are you serious, Fee?!
マジかよ フィー
This course is clear, I take it,
Miss Control Section?
進路は
クリアになってるんでしょうね？
管制課さん
（クレア）もちろんです
Of course.
アイ コピー
I copy.
よろしく～
Thanks so much!
（ハチマキ）お前 親の七光は
大嫌いじゃなかったのか？
I thought you hated people who
ride on their parents' coattails.
（クレア）ええ 今でもそうよ
Yes. I still do.
Then why...
（ハチマキ）だったら…
（クレア）出世したいの
I want to move up
the ranks.
はっ…
Director Dolf doesn't care about your
connections or academic background.
ドルフ事業部長は
コネや学歴に縛られない人よ
結果を出せば 彼は評価してくれる
All that matters to him
is if you deliver results.
What're you gonna do
once you're at the top?
（クレア）余計なお世話ね
That's none of your concern, is it?
私たち もう終わったはずでしょ？
You and I are over, as I recall.
はっ…
俺が終わらせたんじゃねえよ
I wasn't the one
who ended it.
See anything?
どうですか？
うーん 確か
上の出っ張っているところだと…
I'm pretty sure it was towards the top,
up by that part that sticks out.
Please enlarge the area
around the receiver.
レシーバーの部分を
拡大してください
Coming right up...
はいはい
ん？
What the heck
is that?
何ですか？ あれ
A camera.
It's Galaxy's latest model.
（コリン）カメラだよ
I forgot it here when we were
out on that spacewalk.
こないだ 宇宙遊泳やったときに
置き忘れちゃってさ
You forgot it? What did
the instructor say about it?!
（ハチマキ）置き忘れたって
インストラクターは？
He was a lowlife just like you,
so he went back to the ship ahead of us.
君みたいに下品だったから
先に船に戻しちゃった
Honestly, that man
was so irresponsible.
でも ほんと 無責任なやつだよね
Amateurs like us were bound
to leave something behind.
こっちは素人なんだから
忘れ物ぐらいするさ
Um... Wasn't there a
pre-spacewalk checklist?
あの… 遊泳前の届け出は？
Now that you mention it...
（コリン）
ああ そういや 何か言ってたな
So in other words,
this is all your fault!
（ハチマキ）…てことは
全部 お前のせいだろ！
（タナベ）先輩 ちょっと冷静に
Senpai, please stay calm...
Shut up, rookie!
新入りは黙ってろ
ボルトサイズでもな―
One wrong move, and even something the size
of a bolt can take out an entire spaceship!
一歩 間違ったら
宇宙船をぶっ壊せるんだ！
Do you have any idea how serious a felony...
どれだけの重罪だか…
（コリン）あったま 悪いなあ
- Gosh, you're stupid...
That's why I'm having you people
get it for me on the sly, of course.
だから 君たちなんかに頼んで
こっそり拾ってきてもらうんだろ？
Claire! You expect us to pick up debris
for this likes of this bozo?!
クレア こんなやつのために
デブリを回収しろってのか？
連合は 我が社にとって
大事なクライアントです
INTO is an important client
for our company.
If you consider his father's influence, a little thing
like this is all part of keeping the client happy.
彼の父親の影響力を考えたら
これぐらいは接待のうちです
（タナベ）接待って…
Keeping the client happy?
You certainly spell things
out clearly, Claire-san.
はっきり言うなあ クレアさんは
Well, it's people like her who know which side
their bread is buttered on that you can trust.
まっ そういう損得の
分かってる人のほうが―
信用できるけどね
Aren't you at all embarrassed about making
your father clean up your messes for you?!
お前 自分の父親にケツ拭かせて
恥ずかしくないのか？
（コリン）ハッ 幼稚な質問
What a childish question!
Think about it. People who are smart,
run fast, or are good at music...
よく考えなよ 頭がいいやつ―
足が速いやつ
絵や音楽ができるやつ―
...all inherited those abilities
from their parents.
みんな
親から才能をもらってるんだ
It's the same with
money and power.
金や権力も同じことさ
Don't try to rationalize it.
Counting on your parents is...
理屈こいてんじゃねえ
親に頼るなんて
Rationalize?
I'm not rationalizing anything.
（コリン）
出たよ 理屈じゃないって
Even if your parents have power,
you shouldn't use it.
親の力ってのは
あっても使わねえもんだろ
Capitalizing on
your parents is...
親の七光じゃ…
やめなよ
それ以上 言うと ひがみになるよ
Let it go. Any more of this, and you'll make us
think that you have an inferiority complex.
（ハチマキ）
くっ… 何だと？ こら！
Say what, you bastard?!
Senpai!
先輩
（フィー）もういい 私が出る
That's enough!
I'll go out!
あっ…
（タナベ）フィーさん？
Fee-san?
Yuri, get up here.
Take control of Toy Box.
ユーリ こっちに来て
ToyBox(トイボックス) お願い
Huh? Um, I copy.
（ユーリ）えっ ああ アイ コピー
Well done, Captain.
That was a wise decision.
さすが船長 賢明な判断ね
（ハチマキ）チェッ 見損なったよ
I'm disappointed! I can't believe you're
sucking up to the bigshot, too.
あんたまで偉いさんにさ
Senpai...
（タナベ）先輩
I'm not talking to somebody who's been
wagging her tail from the get-go.
（ハチマキ）
はなっから尻尾振ってるやつが
話しかけるな
Hachi, what's that
out there?
（フィー）ハチ あれは何？
（ハチマキ）あ？
That's debris,
isn't it?
あれは デブリじゃないの？
No matter who left it there
or why it was left there,
たとえ誰が そしてどんな理由で
残した物だとしても―
...it doesn't change the fact
that debris is dangerous.
デブリが危険なことに
変わりはないわ
Or that somebody has
to go out and retrieve it.
そして 誰かが回収しなければ
ならないことも
I'm not about to leave that debris
sitting out there.
私は あのデブリを放っておけない
Hachi, what would
you do?
ハチ あんたは どうするの？
くっ…
DS-12, now routing from...
Umbilical access, ECLS systems
connection confirmed.
Good work!
- Welcome back!
（ラビィ･課長）
お疲れさまでした！
I'm seriously exhausted...
（コリン）
あ～ マジに疲れちゃいましたよ
In that case, please choose
whichever drink strikes your fancy!
（ラビィ）
では お好みのドリンクを
Also, while I realize that
this is a shabby gift...
それと これ
つまらない物ですが お父様に…
...please give them
to your father.
（コリン）何？ それ
What are they?
セブン名物の
宇宙シュークリームです
Seven's local delicacy,
Cosmic Cream Puffs.
The cream is made in zero gravity,
so the moderate amount of air...
無重力で
クリームを仕立てていますので―
適度に空気が…
（コリン）かさばるなあ
They're way too bulky.
Just ship them to our house.
自宅に届けてよ
Oh, that never
occured to us...
あっ これは気づきませんで
We'll send them
to your home at once!
早速 ご自宅のほうにでも
（課長）どうだった？ 愛ちゃん
How did it go, Ai-chan?
Did Hachi
behave himself?
（ラビィ）
ハチは おとなしくしてたかい？
Well...
Yes, pretty much...
まあ… まあ なんとか
（コリン）フンッ！
You didn't have to
go to the trouble!
（ラビィ）あっ これは わざわざ
This is an honor, Director!
（課長）恐縮です 事業部長
We've returned after successfully
completing all our missions.
（クレア）無事
全ミッションを終えて帰還しました
Well done.
Welcome back, Colin-san.
（ドルフ）ご苦労
おかえりなさい コリンさん
助かりました
父には よく伝えておきますから
You've been a big help.
I'll make sure to tell my father.
Thank you,
I appreciate that.
ありがとうございます
Your chaperone and friends arrived recently and
have been waiting for you at our office block.
先ほどから
我が社のブロックで―
付き添いの方と
ご友人がお待ちです
Welcome back, sir.
（秘書）おかえりなさいませ
（友人たち）ヒュー おかえりー
Welcome back, Colin!
（友人１）コリン おかえり
Hey, I could've gone
to meet you guys.
出迎えなんか よかったのに
（友人１）違うよ
No, no! We were on our way back from having
a new sofa put in my family's cruiser, and...
うちのクルーザーに
新しいソファを入れた帰り
So we stopped by!
（友人２）ついでだってさ
何だ
Oh.
（友人１）
ねえ 私のカメラ 無事だった？
So, was my camera okay?
ああ 丈夫だよね これ
Sure. This thing
is really tough.
放射線チェックもしたけど
中身は全く問題なし
I even did a radioactivity check,
but the contents are completely fine.
（友人１）よかった それって―
Boy, am I glad to hear that!
The files from that last concert are on there!
こないだのコンサートデータも
入ってるんだ
（コリン）なあ 今度は―
Hey, do you want to go into the graveyard
orbit later and shoot off some fireworks?
墓場軌道のほうで
花火をやらないか？
宇宙でもできるやつが
裏ルートで手に入るんだけど…
I got some that'll work in space
through some back channels.
Of all the stupid... I can't believe this guy.
（ハチマキ）ったく…
つきあってられるかっての
Well, I don't know... Space makes me feel queasy.
Chief, how long do you think
he's gonna be here...?
課長 いつまでいるんでしょうか
Don't worry, I've got some
great medicine for that!
Ai-chan!
愛ちゃん
（ラビィ）接待 接待
Humor him, humor him!
Besides, it'll make
even more debris.
（友人１）
また デブリ出しちゃったりして
No problem! If that happens, I'll just
have these guys clean it up again!
大丈夫 そんときは
また こいつらに回収させるから
（ハチマキ）くっ…
That's not very gracious
of you.
（友人１）感謝ないの
These people can make a living
because there's space debris.
（コリン）
デブリがあるおかげで―
この人たちは
暮らしていけるわけだからさ
We should send more work their way.
You know, volunteer debris!
仕事ぐらい回してあげなきゃ
ボランティアデブリってね
ヒャハハハッ…
てめえ！
You son of a...
Senpai!
先輩！
（クレア）ハチ！
Hachi!
やめろ！
Don't!
He's an INTO bigwig!
連合のお偉いさんなんだよ！
Hoshino-kun!
（ドルフ）星野(ほしの)君
理解しなさい 自分の立場を
You need to understand your place.
Don't you have
any pride?!
あんたには
プライドってもんがないのか！
（友人３）ヒュー
You're so awesome,
mister!
おにいさん カッコいいー
Senpai!
（タナベ）先輩！
（ハチマキ）黙ってろ！ 新入り
Stay out of this,
rookie!
So, what are you
going to do now?
（コリン）…で？
どうするつもり？ ここから
I'm gonna turn you over
to the INTO police!
（ハチマキ）
連合警察に突き出してやる
Oh...?
（コリン）へえ
Covering up debris evidence is a felony.
You'll get at least five years in prison, pal.
デブリの証拠隠しは重罪だ
実刑で ５年は堅いぞ
（コリン）無駄だよ
ほんと あったま悪いなあ
Not likely.
You really are dumb, aren't you?
親父は
連合警察にも顔が利くんだ
My old man has a lot of pull
with the INTO police, too.
Besides, according to the records,
I was never aboard the ship, remember?
それに 記録上
僕は 船に乗ってないんだろ？
訴えても勝ち目はないよ
You could take me to court,
but you won't win.
Don't think that you can get away with anything
you want just because your dad is some bigwig!
（ハチマキ）親父が偉いからって
何でも自由になると思うなよ！
In that case, why not beat me
and kick me all you want?
（コリン）
だったら 殴るなり 蹴るなり―
好きにしたら？
It would cost you your job,
of course...
君の仕事 なくなっちゃうけどね
（ハチマキ）くっ…
ああ それとも 辞めたいのかな？
Oh, or would you rather quit,
instead?
That way, your parents would never know
that you collect garbage in space.
宇宙でゴミ拾いなんて
親にも ないしょだったりして
ああ？
わあ そーだ そーだ
Yeah, that's telling him!
You should know
your place!
身の程をわきまえろっつうの
You do the same pathetic job,
day in and day out.
毎日 毎日
くだんない仕事を ちまちまとさ
Is space so important to you
that you'd stoop to doing even that?
そんなにまでして
宇宙にしがみついていたいのかな
Pathetic.
みっともない
Shall I give you some leads
for a new job?
よかったら 仕事 紹介しようか？
At this rate, you people are really gonna
turn into pieces of space trash.
このままじゃ ほんとに君たちは
宇宙のゴミ野郎になっちゃうよ
（ハチマキ）くっ… てめえ！
That does it, you son of a...
うるさーいっ！
Shut up!
うっ… ぐわぁ
あっ…
（ラビィ･課長）あーっ…
（クレア）あなた なんてことを
What have you done?!
えっ…
（タナベ）ふっ！
（コリン）うっ あっ…
な… なんで君が殴っちゃうわけ？
W-Why did YOU hit me?
I was just about to
get this guy fired...
せっかく こいつを
クビにしてやろうと…
You don't have any idea
what you're talking about!
何 わけ分かんないこと
言ってんですか！
Debris collectors are
as cool as they come!
デブリ屋は 最高にカッコいいです
We make space safe!
We protect people's lives!
宇宙を安全にするんです
人の命を守ってるんです
It's a thankless job,
but we do it anyway!
縁の下の力持ちなんですよ？
ちょ… ちょっと？
H-Hey, wait a minute...
Somebody who does nothing but talk about
his father is the real space trash!
（タナベ）お父さんのことばっかり
言ってる人こそ 宇宙のゴミです！
So I'm gonna take out
the garbage!
だったら 私が掃除してあげます
そ… 掃除って？
T-Take out...?
Stop it, Ai-chan!
やめてよ 愛ちゃん
He's the son of
the INTO chairman!
連合議長の息子さん… んぐぐ
Okay, daddy's boy.
おい ボンボン よく覚えとけ
Get this through your skull.
We don't pick up debris
to make your life easier!
俺たちは お前のために
デブリを拾ってんじゃねえ
くっ…
What're you gonna do, Colin?
（友人２）どうすんだよ コリン
んん…
カッコいいとこ 見せてよね
Yeah, show us
what you're made of!
（コリン）ド… ドルフさん
D-Dolf-san, what will Technora
do about this?
テクノーラ社としては
どうなんですか？
これって 社外の人に対する
暴力事件ですよね？
This is a case of violence
against a non-employee.
We're terribly sorry about this.
We'll give him a disciplinary...
誠に申し訳ありません
早急に処分を…
（フィー）
事件なんて あったかしら？
Oh, did something
happen here?
（クレア）えっ…
（コリン）何言ってんだ？ お前
What are you
talking about?
Um...
（タナベ）あの…
（ユーリ）そうですよね
Yes, that's right.
Nothing happened here.
何もなかったはずですが
事業部長 記録では ここには
我が社の人間しかおりません
Director, according to the records,
no one was here but us employees.
Therefore, no violence against
non-employees could have taken place.
故に 部外者に対する暴力など
起こりようがありません
違いますか？
Am I right?
あっ そういうことに
なるんですか？
Oh, that's how
you'll explain it?
Don't try to mess
with me!
ふざけるな！
おわっとっと… わ わ… ちょっと
H-Hey, somebody
stop me!
だ… 誰か ちょ わ わ わ…
（友人５）キャハハ
何やってんだ？ あれ
What're you doing?
（友人５）キャハハ
何やってんだ？ あれ
おい コリン 頑張れよ
C'mon, Colin!
Hang in there!
おい コリン 頑張れよ
I'm so disappointed...
幻滅～
Y-You can try to hush this up, but it's
not going to work, you hear me?!
（コリン）
お… お前ら もみ消そうたって
そうは いかないからな
Then bring it on,
you little punk!
じゃあ 出るとこ出てやろうか
このガキ！
Do that, and the whole Debris Section
will testify against you.
そのときは
デブリ課全員で証言してやる
（ラビィ･課長）うっ ううっ…
卑怯(ひきょう)じゃないか こら！
That's playing dirty,
damn it!
What the hell?
You jerks...!
何だ くそ この うわっ…
このーっ！
You jerks!
（アナウンス）
間もなく テクノーラ社―
Next stop,
Technora office block.
オフィスブロックです
I'm terribly sorry. Please give the
Chairman my sincerest apologies.
（ドルフ）誠に失礼いたしました
議長にも
よろしく お伝えください
（秘書）
いえ こちらこそ助かりました
ありがとうございます
No, you've done us a great service.
Thank you.
Huh? Where'd everyone go?
（コリン）あれ？ みんなは
皆さん 急用ができたとかで
They all left, claiming
urgent business.
What? How could they...
何だよ… 何だよ それ
Well, we'll excuse
ourselves now.
では 私どもは これで
覚えてろよ
テクノーラ社なんて―
You'd better remember this!
I can drive Technora out of space with just a word!
簡単に
宇宙から追い出せるんだからな
That's quite enough, sir.
そこまでです お坊ちゃま
Any further statements will have only
your own self-confidence to back it up.
これ以上 発言するには―
あなたご自身が
力を持つしかありません
Just write this off as a valuable
learning experience.
いい勉強になったと思って
わきまえてください
Or would you prefer that I report
everything to your father?
それとも お父様に 全て
報告したほうがよろしいですか？
あっ…
（クレア）申し訳ありません
私が間に入っていれば…
I can offer no excuses, sir.
If I had only stepped in more quickly...
（ドルフ）謝罪はいい
その分 働いて返してみせろ
Don't apologize.
Make up for it by working even harder.
Yes, sir.
はい あの…
星野八郎太(はちろうた)の処分は
Um, what is to be done
with Hoshino Hachirota?
クリフォード議長は
息子などと違って―
Unlike his son,
Chairman Clifford
is a calculating man.
計算の立つお方だよ
はっ？
Sir?
Rather than force us to fire an employee, it's
to his advantage to consider ourselves even.
社員を処分させるより―
これで うちとの貸し借りなしと
したほうが得
That's probably what
he's thinking.
そう考えるだろうな
そうですか
Oh, I see.
はあ～
How long are you
gonna keep moping?
（フィー）
いつまで落ち込んでんだよ
私だって 喫煙室のことは
もう諦めてるってのに
Look at me, I've already given up
on that smoking room.
Besides, nothing is going to change our status
as Half Section at this point.
（ユーリ）
今更 半課としての扱いが
変わるわけじゃないですしね
（タナベ）すいません 思わず…
I'm sorry,
I wasn't thinking...
（課長）
なんで我慢できないかなあ
Why couldn't you
hold it in...?!
Letters of resignation!
The work team should resign!
辞表だ！ 現場組は辞表を出せ
Do that, and we might be able
to get them to forgive us!
それでなんとか 許してもらうんだ
ええっ！？
（ハチマキ）こういうときって―
At times like this, aren't the bosses supposed
to step in and take responsibility?
普通 上司が
責任 取るんじゃねえの？
Oh, really?
（ユーリ）そうか…
Captain.
船長
（フィー）係長
Manager.
Chief.
課長
（課長）
ええっ！？ なんで僕なの？
Why does it have
to be me?!
You're the man who's ultimately
in charge, so take one for the team!
（ラビィ）
最高責任者ですから ここは潔く
（タナベ）あの… 減俸とかじゃ
Um, what about a pay cut
or something?
Good idea! We'll all give up
our bonuses!
（課長）あっ それいい
全員 ボーナスなしってことで
I can't do that!
（ラビィ）
そんな 養育費が払えなくなる
I won't be able to
make my child support payments!
Aw, I don't care anymore.
Wanna go grab some food?
もう どうでもいいや
飯 食いに行かないか？
あっ？
Yeah, good idea.
Work's over, after all.
そうだね 仕事 終わってるし
Fee-kun, wait a minute!
フィー君 ちょっと
We'll let you and the Chief
take it from here.
あとは あんたと課長に任せた
（ハチマキ）よーし 決まった
Okay, I've got it!
Hey, wait a minute!
久しぶりに
一般ブロックまで食べに行くか
What say we go eat
in the common block for once?
No! Anything but a pay cut!
（フィー）ユーリも来るでしょ？
（ユーリ）もちろん
You coming, too, Yuri?
Of course.
Lets splurge
a little today.
今日は ちょっとぜいたくに
いきましょうか
ラビィちゃん
Lavie-chan...
Does it really have
to be a pay cut...?
減俸ですかねえ やっぱ
（課長･ラビィ）はあ～
Hey, Tanabe!
You come, too!
（ハチマキ）おい タナベも来いよ
（タナベ）えっ？
The food in the common block
is a little expensive, but it's great.
（ハチマキ）一般ブロックの飯は
ちょっと高いけど うまいんだよ
You've never eaten there.
Right, Tanabe?
まだ行ったことないだろ？
タナベはよ
"Tanabe"?
タナベって…
はい！
Coming!
You're paying,
right, Senpai?
もちろん 先輩のおごりですよね？
As if. This is coming out
of your severance pay!
（ハチマキ）バーカ
お前の退職金で食べるんだよ
What's that supposed
to mean?!
（タナベ）何ですか それ！？
（３人の笑い声）
♪～
♪グッと水を飲み干し
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Fly Me to the Moon
（シア）宇宙船だよ
名前だって付けたんだもん
This is a spaceship! I even gave it a name!
I told you before, kid, this isn't
a spaceship, it's a rescue ball.
だから これは
宇宙船じゃなくて―
救命ボールなの
Cut! Cut!
（監督）
カーット！ カット
But we decided to die
in space!
（父親）だから宇宙で
死のうって決めたんだ
Well, not everybody in the universe is a sweetheart, you know?
まあ 世の中―
親切な人ばかりじゃ
ないからね
（ハチマキ）ガアーッ！
（女性）いやーっ！
先輩が
がさつで乱暴なのは―
I knew you were rude and had no manners,
but I never thought you were capable of this!
分かってましたけど―
まさか
こんなことするなんて！
You bastard!
てめえ！
Even if you do that, there's nowhere that you can run!
（チェンシン）
そんなことしたって―
どこにも逃げられないぞ！